

lew York. New York

🛮 +1 516-859-6058 | 🔀 anagi202@gmail.com | 😭 alinagi.com | 🖸 dontcallmebigguy | 🛅 ali-nagi

# Summary .

Ali is a high-energy, outspoken engineer and designer with a passion for creating beautiful, frictionless experiences. He enjoys talking to people and iterating on new ideas. He looks forward to impactful work and meaningful contributions.

# **Public Projects**

2018 **nexen.bnymellon.com**, Developed common components for unified business platform

2017 **developer.bnymellon.com**, Part of the engineering team to build BNY Mellon's first developer site

2017 **Pie Storm**, A humble attempt to gamify charitable donations

# Work Experience \_

BNY Mellon New York, NY

#### FULL-STACK ENGINEER / DESIGNER - USER EXPERIENCE TEAM

June 2017 - Present

• Design and develop an internal Material Design-based UI component library in Angular 2+ for use by hundreds of developers.

- Migrate existing UI from Angular.js to Angular 2+.
- Design and develop business-facing UI
- Create business-facing prototypes using Axure RP and Sketch, conduct client-facing user-interaction research using in-house UX lab.
- Implement and deploy RESTful APIs in Python (Flask) and Go.

BNY Mellon New York, NY

#### ASSOCIATE - TECHNOLOGY LEADERSHIP PROGRAM

June 2016 - June 2017

- Database-as-a-Service: Automated secure MongoDB deployment on BNY Mellon's internal cloud for use by development teams.
- Developer Console: Full-stack Go + Angular development of a developer-facing web app.
- User Experience: Designed Angular components and implemented with full Karma test coverage.

BNY Mellon New York, NY

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER - USER EXPERIENCE TEAM

June - August, 2014 - 2016

- Utilized Phaser HTML5 game engine to create an internal educational game for employees to learn about concepts such as RESTful APIs.
- Deployed educational game to internal cloud platform for testing by early user group.

## The Polytechnic Reporter

New York, NY

### **EXECUTIVE EDITOR AND DESIGNER**

August 2013 - May 2016

- Served as final editor for newspaper with circulation in the thousands.
- Designed and published layouts for staff writers using Adobe InDesign.

# Skills\_

**Programming** Python, Go, JavaScript, TypeScript

**Front-end** Angular, Angular-Material, NPM, Bower, WebPack, Bootstrap

**UX + Design** Axure, Sketch, GIMP, Adobe Suite

**Mobile** Android, Flutter

## **Education**

# **New York University**

New York, New York

**B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE** 

August 2012 - May 2016

# Interests\_

**Hobbies** Physical fitness, hiking, drawing

**Passions** High-quality designs, blending art and engineering